### **Luke C Plummer**

229 Vassar st.
Cambridge MA, 02139
413-835-1795 | <u>lukulele@mit.edu</u>

#### **Profile**

Luke is a master ukulele player, robotics designer, and audio engineer, whose creativity knows no bounds. He is passionate about his life and engineering endeavors, and enthusiastic about learning new skills and developing unique ways to integrate his many interests. Luke has background in mechanical design, music production and programming, but beyond his technical experience he is a well-developed writer and communicator.

### Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

September 2011-June 2014

Candidate for Bachelor of Science in Mechanical engineering with a concentration in computer science.

#### Relevant coursework:

2.001 (Mechanics and Materials I)
2.003 (Dynamics and Control I)
2.004 (Dynamics and Control II)
2.004 (Dynamics and Control II)
2.004 (Dynamics and Control II)
2.009 (Electronics for Mechanical
Engineers)
6.005 (Software Construction)
2.004 (Dynamics and Control II)
2.009 (Electronics for Mechanical
Engineers)
2.008 (Electronic Music Composition)

### Skills

- Design of small and large scale, mixed analog/digital audio systems for live performance and recording
- Music production from tracking to mastering and creative production
- Programming Languages: Java, Python, Objective C, JavaScript, Quick Basic, Max/MSP
- Software skills: Solidworks, XCode and COCOA Interface Builder, Microsoft Office
- Media Software: Digital Performer, ProTools, Cubase, REAPER, Kontakt, Final Cut Pro, Unity
- Mechanical design of bicycles and sustainable bike technologies, robotics

### **Experience**

# MIT Media Lab: Opera of the Future

January 2011 - Present

Undergraduate Researcher and Audio Systems Engineer

Software, hardware and sound design, and live sound engineering for internationally performed multi-media productions: *Music | Machines, Spheres and Splinters,* and the opera *Death and the Powers*.

# **MIT Logarhythms**

January 2011 - Present

**Executive and Musical Producer** 

Member and studio manager of the MIT Logarhythms, all-male collegiate a cappella group. Manage production of studio albums from concept to tracking to mastering.

### MIT D-Lab: Cycle Ventures

October 2011 - January 2012

Mechanical Project Engineer

Mechanical design and manufacturing projects with a team to develop low-cost rickshaw design improvements.

Projects including power measurement, 3D truss frame, and front suspension. Implementation of projects in Guwahati, India at the *Rickshaw Bank* factory, a project of the NGO *Center for Rural Development*.

Research with local builders and rickshaw drivers to evaluate effectiveness and ease of construction with new designs.